Do you want a friend whom you could tell everything to, like your deepest feelings and thoughts?
Or are you afraid that your friend would laugh at you, or would not understand what you're
going through?
Anne Frank wanted the first kind,
so she made her diary her best friend.
Anne lived in Amsterdam in the Netherlands during World War II.
During that time the only true friend was her diary.
She said, “I don’t want to set down a series of facts in a diary as most people do,
but I want this diary itself to be my friend,
and I shall call my friend Kitty.” Now read how she felt
after being in the hiding place since July 1942.
Thursday 15, June, 1944 Dear kitty,
I wonder if it’s because I haven’t been able to be outdoors
for so long that I’ve grown so crazy about everything to do
with nature.
I can well remember that there was a time when a deep blue sky,
the song of the birds, moonlight and flowers could never have kept me spellbound.
That’s changed since I was here.
But as the moon gave far too much light,
I didn’t dare open a window.
I didn’t go downstairs until the window had to be shut.
It’s no pleasure looking through these any longer because nature is one thing
that really must be experienced.